Now the news, I'm Doh Hongyu.
Hamas has announced that its negotiating delegation survived what it called the Israeli assassination attempt in Qatar.
But six others were killed, including members of the group's escorts and a Qatari security officer.
Among the dead was Hamam al-Hayyya, son of Hamas political bureau member Khalil al-Hayyya.
Hamas said the attack occurred while its delegation was discussing a new U.S. proposal, presented by President Donald Trump, accusing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government of attempting to sabotage international mediation.
It condemned the strike as an assault on the sovereignty of Qatar and held Washington jointly responsible.
The announcement came after Israel confirmed an attack in Doha, targeting the Hamas headquarters in the Qatari capital.
The Israeli military described the blasts as an attempt to assassinate Hamas leaders.
President Benjamin Netanyahu's office said the action was a wholly independent Israeli operation.
A senior Israeli official said U.S. President Donald Trump gave the green light for the strikes.
The White House press secretary said the U.S. military informed the Trump administration that Israel was striking Hamas targets located in a section of Doha.
She said Trump immediately directed special envoy Steve Wittkov to inform Qatar of the attack.
But the Qatari foreign ministry denied reports, claiming Doha had prior knowledge of the Israeli airstrikes on the Qatari capital, saying the only contact from a U.S. official came while explosions had already begun.
Nadia Swan reports.
We're hearing that President Trump, the United States, was told about the attack in advance and that Steve Wittkov, President Trump's special envoy, was to have told Qatar about the attack as well in advance.
However, a Qatari statement says that they weren't told about the attack in advance.
They only really knew about it as the attacks and the strikes were underway.
So President Trump has apparently spoken to Netanyahu.
He's also spoken to Qatar's Amir and said that a strike like that will not happen on Qatari territory again.
Qatari Prime Minister Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdul Rahman al-Tani says the country will respond to the Israeli strike on Doha on Tuesday and deter future attacks.
He said Qatar will not tolerate any violations of its sovereignty and that the country is forming a team to pursue legal actions in response to the Israeli strike.
He added that mediation on a ceasefire and prisoner exchange in Gaza will continue, but no talks are underway currently after the airstrike.
Qatar has condemned the strike as a serious threat to residents and a violation of sovereignty.
The strike has drawn swift international condemnation, including the UN, the Arab League, and countries such as Iran, Saudi Arabia, Egypt, Jordan, and Turkey.
The 80th session of the UN General Assembly has opened at its headquarters in New York.
The theme is better together 80 years and more for peace, development, and human rights.
This year marks the 80th anniversary of the founding of the UN.
A high-level week will kick off on September 22, when world leaders will gather to attend the general debate and a series of conferences.
French President Emmanuel Macron has nominated Defense Minister Sebastien Le Corqneau as the new prime minister.
This comes after he accepted the resignation of François Bayhout, the country's fourth prime minister in less than two years.
Bayhout lost the confidence vote in the National Assembly.
Parliament ousted him over a budget plan seeking to save billions of euros per year in government spending.
Bayhout argued the excessive debt threatens the country.
China's foreign ministry says BRICS is an important platform for cooperation among emerging markets and developing countries.
It also said the virtual leader summit will inject new impetus into the high-quality development of Greater BRICS cooperation.
Chinese President Xi Jinping addressed the meeting on Monday, proposing efforts to uphold multilateralism, openness, and solidarity to poor strength for development.
The foreign ministry said China is willing to make joint efforts to implement the consensus of the summit and make new contributions for an equal and orderly multipolar world and inclusive economic globalization.
And that's the news.
I'm Do Hongyu.