Now the news.
I'm Shane Bigum, General Secretary Xi Jinping of the Communist Party of China's Central Committee has called for persistent efforts to implement the guiding principles of the Central Party leadership's eight-point decision on improving conduct.
He made the remarks in an instruction to a meeting on party building in Beijing on Friday.
Chinese Vice Foreign Minister Ma Xiaoshu has called for strengthening the role of the United Nations, saying reforms are needed to help the world body tackle global challenges.
He says the UN's effectiveness depends on member states upholding the UN Charter and observing international law and the basic norms governing international relations.
This year marks the 80th anniversary of the Allied victory of World War II and also the founding of the UN, the direct outcome of the war.
Meanwhile, the Chinese diplomat says the country has taken the lead in practicing true multilateralism and it firmly supports the UN in playing a central role in international affairs.
The Vice Foreign Minister says China's committed to peaceful development.
Ma also says a community with a shared future for humanity offers new wisdom to global governance and it presents a new vision for a better world.
Chen Yilin reports.
Vice Foreign Minister Ma Xiaoshu has briefed the media about China's commitment to uphold peaceful development.
In terms of building a community of shared future for humanity, he highlighted that at this critical historical juncture, this concept has charted the course for global peace and development.
What began as a China initiative has now evolved into a global consensus.
He elaborated that for eight consecutive years, this concept is included in the UN General Assembly resolutions as well as the declarations of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization.
And the concept also consistently incorporated in the declarations of BRICS leaders meeting for eight times.
And it also brings new wisdom and new vision for building a better world.
China Coast Guard's conducted law enforcement patrols in the territorial waters of Huangyangdao and other nearby islands.
The CCG said it stepped up its presence around the islands in the South China Sea since early August.
It said it's carrying up patrols in line with laws and regulations.
Thailand's constitutional courts removed suspended Prime Minister Phaetongtuan Shenowat from office after finding her guilty of ethical misconduct over a controversial phone call with former Cambodian leader, Hoon Sen.
In the leaked call, Phaetongtuan was heard discussing the Thailand-Cambodia border crisis with Hoon Sen back in June.
She also described the Thai military as the opposite side and blamed them for escalating tensions across the border.
The ruling on Friday made Phaetongtuan the fifth Prime Minister since 2008 to be stripped of office by Thai judges.
Chao Rat-Yong Jirenon has more from Bangkok.
We have another dismissed Prime Minister here in the country, Phaetongtuan Shenowat, has been found guilty of not meeting the ethical standards of her position as Prime Minister.
What we know so far in terms of the announcement made by the constitutional court is that they had defined the ethical standards of a Prime Minister.
They said that what the actions that she had taken was reflecting the lack of unity between the government and military at the time.
UN Secretary General Antony Guterres has urged Israel to ensure an immediate and permanent ceasefire in Gaza.
He also called for unobstructed humanitarian access into Gaza and unconditional release of hostages.
Guterres warned that famines aggrim reality in Gaza, saying Israel has clear obligations to provide food, water, medicine and essential supplies.
The Israeli military is in the initial stages of a new attack on Gaza City.
According to a military spokesperson, the Israeli military will intensify its strikes until it brings back all the hostages and dismantles Hamas.
Meanwhile, a statement from the Israel Defense Forces says the daily 10-hour humanitarian pause in Gaza City is canceled.
The statement also says the city from now on constitutes a dangerous combat zone.
Britain, France and Germany have triggered a process that could reimpose full UN sanctions on Iran within 30 days.
The move is a response to what they call Tehran's violations of the 2015 nuclear deal.
Iran says the European move is illegal and a blow to diplomacy.
The US State Department confirmed the country will not participate in the United Nations periodic review of its human rights record.
The US is the first UN member state to withdraw from that process.
The review requires all 193 member states to submit reports every four to five years.
And that's the news.
I'm Shane Bigger.