Now the news. I'm Shane Bigum. Israel has confirmed an attack in Qatar targeting the Hamas headquarters in Doha. The Israeli military described the blast as an attempt to assassinate Hamas leaders. Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said the action was a wholly independent Israeli operation. A senior Israeli official said U.S. President Donald Trump gave the green light for the strikes. Al Jazeera television citing a Hamas source said the attack targeted the group's negotiating delegation in Qatar. Jonathan Ragev reports from Tel Aviv.
All of the top Hamas officials and mediators were there. Some reports are saying everybody was killed. Other reports are saying no one was injured. After the killing of Ismail Aniyah last year in Tehran and the Hamas officials which were killed in Beirut, there are only two remaining safe places for the Hamas officials. One is Turkey, the other is Qatar. So far Israel refrained from doing any offensive operation in Qatar due to the role that it has in the mediation. If the reports are correct then this is no longer true. Qatar has condemned the Israeli strikes, calling them a criminal assault. United Nations Secretary General Antony Guterres, the Arab League's Secretary General and countries including Iran, Saudi Arabia and Jordan also denounced the airstrikes. Israel has ordered the demolition of homes in two West Bank villages linked to gunmen who carried out a deadly shooting in Jerusalem.
Israel also said it will revoke hundreds of work permits for Palestinian residents. Attackers opened fire at a bus stop near an Israeli settlement in Jerusalem on Monday, killing six Israelis. Hamas's armed wing has claimed responsibility for the shooting.
Protester is in Nepal, have set the nation's parliament building ablaze. After Prime Minister K.P. Sharma Ali resigned amid protests that left at least 19 people dead. Young demonstrators defied curfews, demanding an end to social media bans and government corruption. Despite the restoration of social platforms after the violence, protests continued in Kathmandu with police reporting cases of arson and attacks. The resignations of the Interior Minister and two other cabinet colleagues on Monday intensified the political crisis. The government had initially imposed the social media ban last week, claiming the platforms failed to register with authorities. Kalyan Raj Sharma reports from the capital city.
After Prime Minister resignation, they are discussing about who will be the next new leaders. As we heard in the social media now, Mayor Balin in Kathmandu, he is trying to lead and he is expecting to lead the dissolve the parliament and make the new government.
But the Kathmandu condition is very, very worst. Now everywhere is a fire and protesters are doing continuous demonstration and burning the every leader's house and almost all three places like legislation, cabinet, all they have under their control. China's foreign ministry says BRICS is an important platform for cooperation among emerging markets in developing countries. It also said the virtual leaders summit will inject new impetus, single the high quality development of greater BRICS cooperation. Chinese President Xi Jinping addressed the meeting on Monday, proposing efforts to uphold multilateralism, openness and solidarity to pool strength for development. The foreign ministry said China is willing to make joint efforts to implement the consensus of the summit and make new contributions for an equal and orderly multipolar world and inclusive economic globalization.
Officials are aiming for China's sports industry to top 7 trillion yuan or more than 980 billion US dollars by 2030. The country's top economic regulators said promoting the development of the sports industry and outdoor sports will feature in the 15th five year plan that will begin next year. The nation aims to build around 100 high quality outdoor sports destinations by the end of the five year period. Officials from the National Development and Reform Commission have pledged support through central government funding and other funds.
French media as a president Emmanuel Macron's accepted the resignation of Prime Minister Francois Bayreau, who lost a confidence vote in the National Assembly. Macron said he'll name a successor within a few days. Bayreau was the country's fourth prime minister in less than two years. Parliament ousted him over a budget plan seeking to save billions of euros per year in government spending. Bayreau argued the excessive debt threatens the country.
Municipal leaders and civil rights lawyers in Los Angeles are condemning a US Supreme Court decision that allows immigration agents to continue raids in Southern California.
This accuses them of targeting individuals based on race or language. LA Mayor Karen Bass called the ruling an attack on all residents and attorneys have vowed to appeal.
That's the news. I'm Shane Bigel.