Now the news, I'm Shane Bigum.
China's congratulated a Newton-Chuan Vera Kool on his election as Thai Prime Minister.
A Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said the country stands ready to work with Thailand to carry forward traditional friendship and deepen cooperation.
The spokesperson also called for joint efforts to consolidate the building of the China-Thailand community with a shared future and contribute to regional peace and prosperity.
A Newton leader of the Boomjai Thai Party was elected as Thailand's 32nd Prime Minister on Friday.
Chao Rat-Yong-Jee Ran-Aunt reports from Bangkok.
We are officially now getting the votes confirmed here that the new 32nd Thai Prime Minister for the country, Anu Tin-Chuan Mirgundi, leader of Boomjai Thai Party has won the vote, 311 to the total of 490 seats here in parliament.
As the new Prime Minister, this is quite unprecedented because it's the first time that there is no horse trading, you could say, in politics here in Thailand and that it's going to be a minority government.
Russian President Vladimir Putin has said the country will roll out a visa-free policy for Chinese citizens to reciprocate similar policies from China.
The president was speaking at the Eastern Economic Forum in Russia's Far East.
Putin said the policy reflects friendship between the two countries and it'll further promote people-to-people exchanges and facilitate business and trade activities.
China's rolled out a one-year visa-free policy for Russian citizens with ordinary passports.
The policy takes effect from September 15th.
Portuguese Prime Minister Luiz Montenegro will visit China from Monday to Wednesday.
The official visit comes at the invitation of Chinese Premier Li Cheng.
Chinese Foreign Ministry has called for joint efforts with Portugal to promote strategic mutual trust, deepen friendly exchanges, advance high-quality Belt and Road cooperation, and enrich their partnership.
Official data shows that China's service trade posted solid growth in the first seven months of 2025.
The Commerce Ministry says the country saw a steep increase in the trade of travel-related services.
The volume of trade and services reached nearly 4.6 trillion yuan, or over 644 billion US dollars between January and July, an increase of 8.2%.
The Chinese Embassy in Afghanistan handed over 200,000 US dollars in emergency humanitarian cash assistance to support Afghanistan's earthquake relief efforts.
The Red Cross Society of China provided the assistance.
The handover took place during a meeting between a senior diplomat from the Chinese Embassy and the president of the Afghan Red Crescent Society.
Earlier, the Chinese government said it'll provide 50 million yuan, or roughly 7 million US dollars, in emergency humanitarian aid for Quake-hit Afghanistan.
According to the Afghan Red Crescent Society, the powerful Quake has killed more than 2,200 people and injured more than 3,600 others.
The Iranian Foreign Minister and the European Union Foreign Policy Chief have discussed the latest developments regarding Tehran's nuclear issue.
Syed Abbas-Irachi and Kayak Hollis also exchanged views on Iran's cooperation with the International Atomic Energy Agency.
The meeting in Doha came after France, Britain, and Germany moved to trigger a scheme to reinstate international sanctions on Iran.
French President Emmanuel Macron has announced that 26 countries, mostly from Europe, have formally vowed to deploy troops as part of a future Russian-Ukrainian ceasefire.
The announcement followed a virtual meeting of the coalition of the willing, co-chaired by Macron and British Prime Minister Kirsten Starrer.
Macron said the country is still contributing to a reassurance force that could deploy troops in Ukraine to provide support.
He also said the participants have held a call with US President Donald Trump, and the US is set to finalize its contributions to the security guarantees in the coming days.
Ross Cullen has more from Paris.
It is complicated because the European allies of Ukraine do see it as crucial.
It is also something that Volodymyr Zelensky has said himself.
There has to be US backstop.
There has to be US participation in the security guarantees involvement in the design in the architecture of those security guarantees.
There has been wavering signals from the US.
We heard Donald Trump saying he wasn't ruling out US boots on the ground.
Then he was ruling it out.
He was saying there could be air support without defining if that would be jets and bombers or if that would simply be air defense systems.
British Deputy Prime Minister Angela Reiner has reportedly resigned following a property tax scandal.
Reiner, who also served as housing secretary, stepped down after failing to pay £40,000 in stamp duty on her second home.
And that's the news.
I'm Shane Degas.
Thank you.