Now, the news.
I'm Wen Jie.
Chinese Premier Li Zhang has expressed the country's readiness to strengthen high-level exchanges and strategic communication with North Korea.
He met North Korean leader Kim Jong-un in Pyongyang on Thursday.
Premier Li said the Communist Party of China and the Chinese government have always regarded ties with North Korea from a strategic height and a long-term perspective.
He also said maintaining, consolidating and developing traditional-friendly and cooperative relations between the two countries is China's unwavering policy.
Kim said Pyongyang is willing to maintain close high-level exchanges with Beijing, promote cooperation in various fields, and strengthen multilateral collaboration.
Italian President Sergio Madarella has met Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi in Rome.
Madarella described both nations as ancient civilizations that embrace peace and cooperation.
He also highlighted China's increasingly crucial role in the international community, saying Italy expects China to make greater contributions to global peace and stability.
Wang said China values Italy's influence in Europe and the world, and he called for joint efforts to implement the consensus reached by the two countries' leaders, consolidate partnership and make bilateral relations more stable and resilient.
Hamas says it has received guarantees from mediators and the U.S. government confirming the complete end of the war in the Gaza Strip.
The head of the Hamas negotiating delegation says the guarantees paved the way for the implementation of the first phase of the U.S. plan for a permanent ceasefire.
Khalil Al-Hayya reaffirms Hamas' approval of the agreement reached during the three-day negotiations held in the Egyptian resort city of Shamil Sheikh.
He says the agreement includes a permanent ceasefire, the withdrawal of Israeli forces from the Gaza Strip, the entry of humanitarian aid, the reopening of the Rafa crossing in both directions and a prisoner swap.
Meanwhile, the Israeli government has approved the Gaza ceasefire deal in exchange for the release of all hostages.
Adele Marouki reports.
What comes after the first phase is the most crucial part.
It is the reason why all previous ceasefire agreements have collapsed.
That is the management of Gaza.
Who will take over Gaza?
This armament of the Palestinian armed resistance group, which they said they will not do before establishing an independent Palestinian state.
Israel also objects to any government in Gaza that involves Hamas or the Palestinian authorities.
So there's a lot of reform that has to be done within the Palestinian front so that they can start sending some assurances to Israel that no further attacks will come from this part of the occupied territories towards them.
UN Secretary General Antonio Guterres has said the world body is ready to scale up humanitarian relief to Gazans following the announcement of a ceasefire deal.
Guterres said the UN has the expertise, the distribution networks and community relationships in place to act.
Russian President Vladimir Putin has said Moscow will pay compensation over the crash of an Azerbaijani passenger jet in December.
Putin discussed the causes of the accident with Azerbaijani President Ilham Aliyev during their meeting in Dushanbe.
He said Russia was tracking three Ukrainian drones crossing its border then, and technical malfunctions of Russia's air defense system may have been a factor in the crash.
The Kremlin says there has been no substantive response from Washington to Russia's initiative on the new Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty.
Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov says there is a serious pause in the dialogue process between Russia and the United States.
Commenting on the Ukraine conflict, Peskov says Kiev is not at all drawn to any kind of peace process right now.
Not-going French Prime Minister Sebastian Lacourneau says parliament could eventually reach a deal on a 2026 budget.
On Monday, Lacourneau resigned after less than four weeks on the job.
However, a French President Emmanuel Macron's request, Lacourneau is holding last-stage consultations with key political party leaders.
And that's the news.
I'm Wenzhi.