Now the news. I'm Shane Bigum, Chinese President Xi Jinping has sent a congratulatory letter to LaChina International Fair for Trade and Services, stressing the country's commitment to opening up and global cooperation.
China will advance reforms in free trade pilot zones and national level demonstration zones for the innovative development of trade and services. The president said China will continue opening its services wider in an orderly way, aiming for high quality growth in trade and services. He added that China is ready to work with other countries to promote open and cooperative global trade and build a community with a shared future for humanity.
The report on business climate in China by the American Chamber of Commerce in Shanghai shows that more than one-third of surveyed U.S. firms believe China's policies and regulations toward foreign companies have improved. Amcham Shanghai chair Jeffrey Lehmann said the situation is improving for American companies in terms of tariff barriers, regulatory questions, and intellectual property rights issues. Chen Tong has more.
Over 40 percent of the companies are confident in China opening up further. Over 70 percent of the companies surveyed turn profits in 2024. The U.S. tariffs and economic uncertainties, geopolitical tensions are bringing a lot of challenges, uncertainties to the U.S. companies in China. But they believe China's policies is opening up further, so they are seeing more confidence in the China market. China has condemned the Israeli strikes targeting the Hamas leadership in Doha, saying it firmly opposes Israel's violation of Qatar's sovereignty and security.
The foreign ministry stressed that military action will not bring peace to the Middle East, and dialogue is the only viable path forward. China urged countries to prioritize regional peace and work with the international community to play a constructive role to de-escalate tensions.
An Israeli official said U.S. President Donald Trump okayed the strike on Qatar.
Trump said he received warning of the attack and spoke with the Israeli prime minister and a mere of Qatar after. China says the Beijing-Shangshan forum next week is more inclusive, and will welcome defense officials and military leaders from more than 100 countries, along with representatives from regional and international organizations.
The defense ministry said countries including Vietnam, Russia, Nigeria, and Brazil have confirmed their participation. Discussions will focus on global security governance, security cooperation within Asia Pacific, and maintaining international order.
There will be academic activities themed on the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
China has highlighted its achievements in the development of natural resources during the 14th five-year plan period. China has built a 3,000-kilometer sand control belt around the Tequimacan Desert in the northwest of the country, and the national forest coverage rate has reached 25 percent. Meanwhile, it is safeguarded agricultural and food security with measures to protect farmland and upgrade production capacity. China's marine GDP exceeded 10.5 trillion yuan, around 1.5 trillion US dollars in 2024. The State Council, Taiwan Affairs Office, has responded to a recent global opinion survey showing strong recognition of Taiwan's return to China after World War II. According to the CGTN poll in 40 countries, two-thirds of the 12,000 respondents said they were aware of Taiwan's recovery after the war, with awareness in Asia reaching 73.5 percent. Most respondents agreed that Taiwan's return was a result of the Allied victory, and that any moves toward Taiwan independence would undermine that outcome.
Taiwan Affairs Office spokesperson Chen Ben-Hua criticized the Democratic Progressive Party authorities for promoting Taiwan independence and attempting to alter the cross-strait status quo, saying such actions challenged the post-war international order.
China's consumer inflation fell in August, while factory prices showed signs of stabilization.
The consumer price index fell 0.4 percent, though core inflation, excluding food and energy, rose 0.9 percent, marking the fourth month of increase. The producer price index dropped 2.9 percent, narrowing its decline from July and holding steady on a monthly basis.
Iran and the International Atomic Energy Agency have agreed to resume cooperation.
The announcement came in Cairo, where Iranian Foreign Minister Syed Abbasirachi said the deal protects Iran's sovereignty and nuclear rights.
Egypt's foreign minister welcomed Tehran's willingness to return to talks and pledged to help ease regional tensions. Agency Chief Rafael Grossi confirmed the agreement to restart inspections, calling it a step toward diplomacy and stability.
And that's the news. I'm Shane Digger.