Now, the news.
I'm Wenzhi.
The top leaders of China and North Korea have reaffirmed their friendship and vowed to further develop bilateral relations.
The messages came as Chinese President Xi Jinping held talks with North Korean top leader Kim Jong-un in Beijing.
Kim attended commemorations marking the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese people's war of resistance against Japanese aggression and the world anti-fascist war.
President Xi said the move demonstrated North Korea's firm resolve to safeguard the outcomes of the victory in World War II.
He also said China is willing to strengthen high-level exchanges and strategic communication and enhance mutual understanding and friendship with North Korea.
President Xi added that China has always maintained an objective and impartial stance regarding the Korean Peninsula issue, and it stands ready to continue strengthening coordination with North Korea to strive to maintain peace and stability.
Kim said the friendship between North Korea and China will remain unchanged no matter how the international landscape evolves.
He said his country is willing to work with China to strengthen exchanges and conduct experience sharing, and that North Korea is ready to deepen economic and trade cooperation with China.
Chinese President Xi Jinping says the country is willing to conduct cooperation with all countries in the artificial intelligence sector to boost its sound development and ensure that its outcomes better benefit the people.
He made the remarks in a congratulatory letter to the World's Smart Industry Expo 2025.
President Xi said China will further advance the integration between scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation in the AI sector and use it to empower high-quality social and economic development so as to improve the people's quality of life.
The World's Smart Industry Expo 2025 opened in Chongqing on Friday and will run until Monday.
Voting for the election of a new Thai prime minister has started.
It came two days after the acting prime minister said his caretaker government had moved to dissolve the lower house of parliament.
Thailand has been under political chaos since the constitutional court sacked former prime minister Paitongtuan Shenawa for ethical misconduct about a week ago.
Washington DC has filed a lawsuit against the Trump administration over the deployment of National Guard troops in the US capital.
The district's attorney general said such deployment is unlawful and that the forced military occupation of the District of Columbia violates local autonomy and basic freedoms, which must end.
The attorney general's office said the deployment violates the Home Rule Act, which grants a local government the authority to govern itself, exercising powers of governance within its own administrative area.
The lawsuit was filed less than a month after US President Donald Trump signed an executive order on deploying the National Guard to the US capital to help restore law and order and ensure public safety.
French President Emmanuel Macron has announced that 26 countries, mostly European, have formally vowed to deploy troops as part of a future Russian-Ukrainian ceasefire, though not directly on the front line.
The announcement followed a virtual meeting of the coalition of the willing co-chair by Macron and British Prime Minister Kirsten Stammer.
Macron said the countries will contribute to a reassurance force that could deploy troops in Ukraine or provide support.
He added that the participants have held a call with US President Donald Trump and that the US is set to finalize its contributions to the security guarantees in the coming days.
Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky welcomed the announcement, adding that a meeting with Russian President Volodymyr Putin is necessary for advancing peace efforts.
A Kremlin spokesperson said foreign military units cannot provide security guarantees to Ukraine.
All funiculars in Lisbon have been suspended for technical inspections following a deadly accident that killed 17 people and injured 21 others.
The accident happened when the glory of a nuclear, one of the best-known tourist attractions in the Portuguese capital derailed and overturned.
And that's the news.
I'm Wenzhi.