Now the news, I'm Tian Yu.
China has congratulated Sushila Kaki on becoming the prime minister of Nepal's interim government.
The former chief justice of Nepal took office as the prime minister of the interim government on Friday evening following KP Sharma Olli's resignation.
A Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said, China and Nepal share a time-honored friendship, and China respects the development path chosen independently by the people of Nepal.
The spokesperson also said, China stands ready to work with Nepal to promote the five principles of peaceful coexistence, enhance exchanges and cooperation in various fields, and further advance bilateral relations.
The Chinese foreign minister has urged China and Europe to make their by-choices amid the greatest changes in a century which will demonstrate the responsibilities that both sides should fulfill toward history and their people.
Wang Yi said he and his Slovenian counterpart, Tian Yan Fayon, reached broad consensus after in-depth talks.
Wang said the most important thing is to promote multilateralism and jointly safeguard purposes and principles of the UN Charter.
The Chinese foreign minister also met Slovenian president Natasa Pritch-Mussar during his visit.
Wang said China will stand with the majority of countries to prevent a return to the law of the jungle and defend international fairness and justice.
A military spokesperson says, the Chinese People's Liberation Army's Southern Theater Command conducted routine patrols in the South China Sea on Friday and Saturday.
Tian Jing Li says the Philippines has colluded with countries outside the region for so-called joint patrols spread illegal claims about the South China Sea and undermined peace and stability in the region.
Tian emphasizes, troops of the Southern Theater Command remain on high alert to safeguard China's territorial sovereignty and national security and uphold peace and stability in the South China Sea.
The 2025 China International Fair for Trade and Services concludes in Beijing on Sunday.
The five-day fair in Shogang Park has attracted over 2,000 companies from more than 80 countries and regions.
It showcases nearly 200 innovations from over 2,000 companies.
The focus on AI, healthcare, tourism and smart logistics underscores the role of services as a durable growth engine.
The fair has also highlighted openness and innovation, reinforcing its reputation as a global business platform and a cultural festival.
US Secretary of State Marco Rubio is in Tel Aviv for a two-day visit.
Rubio says the US will continue to support Israel despite President Donald Trump's criticism of the Israeli strike on Doha last week.
Rubio is scheduled to meet Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Hayahu during the trip.
The visit comes before the UN holds a debate on the possible creation of a Palestinian state.
Syria will hold its first parliamentary elections since the fall of former President Bashar Al-Sad nine months ago.
The move is part of the authorities' efforts to gain international recognition and implement economic reforms critical for Syria's reintegration into the global community.
Heider Kazweeney reports from Damascus.
Romania says a drone breached its airspace during a Russian attack on Ukraine.
The Romanian Defense Ministry says the drone did not fly over populated areas and opposed no threat before disappearing from the radar.
A surge is underway for possible debris.
Poland has also protested Russia's alleged drone intrusion, a claim denied by Moscow.
Poland has closed border crossings with Belarus due to joint Russia-Belarus military exercises.
The Federal Aviation Administration has proposed finding Boeing 3.1 million US dollars over safety violations from September 2023 to February 2024.
The FAA said it identified hundreds of quality system breaches at Boeing's 737 factory in Brenton, Washington and a subcontractors factory in Wichita, Kansas.
And that's the news.
I'm Genyu.