Now the news. I'm Wen Jie.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has extended congratulations to the 15th plenary session of the China-Russia Friendship Committee for Peace and Development. President Xi emphasized the committee has stayed true to its founding mission of promoting friendship and cooperation, served the overall interests of China-Russia relations, and consolidated social and popular support for bilateral ties. The Chinese leader said he hopes the committee will take this meeting as an opportunity to actively play the role of the main channel for people-to-people exchanges and contribute to mutual understanding and solidarity. Russian President Vladimir Putin has also extended congratulations to the plenary session.
China and the African Union have pledged to strengthen solidarity in building a more just global governance system and a peaceful world. The commitment was made at a high-level seminar in Addis Ababa, marking the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Antifascist War. The head of the Chinese mission to the AU emphasized the need to remember history and enhance global cooperation to address security challenges. The past 80 years is a period of accelerated advancement in world multiple layerty and economic globalization and also a period during which the global south has been rising and growing in strength. Human society has emerged from the shadows of the Cold War and moved beyond the bipolar standoff, but comprehensive peace and shared prosperity remain elusive. Jungfeng also called on the global south to jointly uphold multilateralism.
Preparations have been in full swing at an airport in central China as part of the country's efforts to provide emergency humanitarian aid to quick hit Afghanistan. The aid includes tents and blankets.
The shipment is scheduled to arrive in the Afghan capital on Sunday morning.
Israel has ordered residents of Gaza City to evacuate south as it prepares for its offensive to capture the territory's largest urban center. The operation is raising major concerns for the safety of the 20 Israeli hostages still believed to be held by Hamas in the city.
Robby Elmengarry reports from Gaza City.
Actually the residents here have been already concerned, highly concerned about a possible or a potential Israeli move that is a very large scale takeover of the city and taken military actions here over the past 24 hours since Israeli army began its operations against the residential towers in Gaza City starting with a mustahat tower that is a high rise and looking down earlier actually they knocked down another tower which is a suicide tower near the headquarters of United Nations in Gaza City. US President Donald Trump has said he will not attend the G20 summit in South Africa later this year. However, Trump said he plans to send Vice President J.D. Vance in his place. The US President also said the country will host next year's G20 summit at his golf club near Miami. South Korean President Lee Jae-myun has ordered a full response after over 300 Korean workers were arrested in a US immigration raid. The operation took place at a Hyundai Motor Car Battery Plant in Georgia on Thursday. South Korean Foreign Minister Cho Hyun said a task force has been formed and he may visit Washington DC if necessary. More than 470 people were detained in the raid, the largest single site enforcement action in US Department of Homeland Security's history. Europe has launched a supercomputer claimed to be the world's fourth fastest.
German Chancellor Friedrich Merz says the historic project has helped Europe catch up with the US and China both leading the AI race. The Jupiter is the region's fastest supercomputer.
International Olympic Committee President Kirstie Coventry has announced the creation of four new working groups as part of the Fit for the Future initiative. The initiative focuses on the Youth Olympic Games, Olympic program, protection of the female category and commercial partnerships and marketing. And that's the news. I'm Won-ji.