Now, the news. I'm Tian Lu. Chinese President Xi Jinping is urging member countries of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization to march toward modernization together by bringing out the best in one another and working together for a shared future. In his keynote speech at the SCO Council of Heads of State meeting, President Xi stressed the Shanghai spirit that emphasizes mutual trust, equality and respect.
Looking back, we have weathered the storms on our journey and emerged stronger because we have adhered to the Shanghai spirit. Looking ahead, we should carry forward the Shanghai spirit in a world fraught with challenges and changes. Forge your head with solid steps and a better tap into the potential of our organization. President Xi announced that China will provide two billion yuan or more than 281 million US dollars in grant to SCO member states this year. He urged all members to seek common ground while setting aside differences and pursue mutual benefit for a better future. As the Chinese saying goes, where will prevails, no boundary holds. Let us stay true to SCO's founding mission. Step up to undertake our duties, promote the sound and sustained development of the SCO with greater resolve and more practical measures, and march steadily toward a brighter tomorrow of a community with a shared future for humanity. The Shanghai Cooperation Organization has grown into the world's largest regional organization with the participation of 26 countries and a combined economic output of nearly 30 trillion US dollars.
Reports from Afghanistan say an earthquake in the eastern province of Kunar has killed at least 250 people. The state-owned Bakhtar news agency says 500 others have been injured across multiple districts. The United States Geological Survey says the magnitude-six quake struck at about midnight local time on Monday, about 27 kilometers east of Jalalabad. Reports say the number of casualties is likely to rise as assessments continue. The biggest flood in the history of Punjab province in eastern Pakistan is threatening the safety and livelihood of 2 million people.
Officials say water levels have risen to all-time highs. Residents have experienced abnormal amounts of rain along with cross-border flooding after an alert from India.
Security and humanitarian sources say the Houthi group arrested several employees of the United Nations World Food Programme. The Houthis are also reportedly holding several staff members of the United Nations Children's Fund in Sanaa. Following an Israeli airstrike on Sanaa that killed the Prime Minister of the Houthi-backed government, Yemeni sources said that the group detained dozens of people on suspicion of collaboration with Israel. A United Nations envoy has condemned the arrests and urged the immediate release of the detainees.
Lebanese parliament speaker Nabi Berry has rejected a US-backed proposal to disarm Hezbollah, saying Lebanon will not give up its weapons under threats. Berry stressed that discussions over Hezbollah's arms could only take place in a calm, consensual framework under the Constitution.
Berry dismissed attempts by foreign powers to pressure Lebanon into concessions.
France is pushing back against what it calls outside interference in Greenland. Foreign Minister Ron Noelle Behal visited the Arctic region and said US maneuvers were disrespectful and unacceptable.
Behal's visit comes as US President Donald Trump has repeatedly expressed interest in controlling Greenland Danish media say at least three Americans have been running influence operations there.
In sports, Chinese shuttler Shi Yuqi won his maiden title after a victory over defending champion Viktor Axelsen at the Badminton World Championships in Paris.
On the women's side, Chen Yufei came runner-up to a king Yamaguchi. The Japanese player became the second woman to win three singles titles at the Worlds after Carolina Marry.
And that's the news. I'm Keanu.