Now the news. I'm Shane Digger, Chinese President Xi Jinping's held bilateral meetings with foreign leaders attending China's Victory Day commemorations in Beijing. President Xi told Vietnam's Leng Kuang that Beijing's ready to work with Hanoi to safeguard the common interests of the global south and contribute more positive energy to the world. During his meeting with Lao President Tong Lung Sisi Lit, President Xi called on the two countries to upgrade key cooperation projects and further unleashed the potential of the China-Laut Railway as a golden corridor. He also met Cuban President Miguel Diaz Canel and the Chinese leader suggested the two sides promote bilateral relations to a higher level and deliver more benefits to the people. The two sides also issued a joint statement on accelerating the building of a China-Cuba community with a shared future. While meeting the Zimbabwean President Xi Jinping and President Emerson Menenggogwa agreed to upgrade ties to an all-weather China-Zimbabwe community with a shared future. The Chinese leader also met presidents of the Republic of Congo in Serbia and the Prime Minister of Slovakia.
China's decided to impose anti-dumping levies on some types of U.S. single-mode optical fibers. The Chinese Commerce Ministry said the decision came after authorities launched an anti-circumvention investigation following a request from a domestic company. The investigation was the first of its kind.
The Iranian president called for implementing the agreements of the recent Shanghai Cooperation Organization Summit. Mazud Pazeshkin said implementation will create favorable prospects for Iran in the economic, security, scientific and tourism areas. He was speaking upon arriving in Tehran after taking part in the summit in Tianjin on Sunday and Monday. The president also attended China's Victory Day commemorations in Beijing on Wednesday.
Mazud Pazeshkin said the deal was a permanent ceasefire and the withdrawal of Israeli forces from Gaza. Hamas is also voiced support for establishing an independent national administration composed of technocrats to take immediate responsibility for managing Gaza's civil affairs. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has dismissed Hamas's statement as spin.
The trial of former Brazilian president Jair Bolsonaro has reached a critical phase. The Supreme Court is considering the verdict and sentencing, which could take some time. Authorities have accused Bolsonaro of plotting a coup after losing the 2022 election. The proceedings are deeply divisive inside Brazil. Paulo Cabral reports from Sao Paulo.
At the end of this trial, former president Jair Bolsonaro and seven other defendants could face prison sentences of more than 40 years. They stand accused of attempting a coup d'etat and several associated crimes, judging them a panel of five Supreme Court justices. The first to speak was Alexandre de Morais, the judge who's led the case and now has to present a report to his peers. It is a highly divisive case in a country already marked by polarization and one with international repercussions. The former president is under house arrest wearing an ankle monitor, a measure imposed by Morais that has outraged Bolsonaro's supporters.
Japan's weather agency says Typhoon Paypa is expected to approach the country's western region and it could make landfall later this week. The Japan Meteorological Agency says a tropical depression over waters east of Amami, Oshima Island has developed into a tropical storm. Weather officials have warned of mudslides and floods in low-lying areas, as well as swole and rivers, wind gusts and high waves.
Cambodian officials say the country attracted fixed asset investment of $7.2 billion in the first eight months of the year. The figure represents an increase of 50% from a year earlier.
The Council for the Development of Cambodia says the Southeast Asian country approved nearly 500 investment projects during the period, generating nearly 340,000 jobs. China remains the top foreign investor in the kingdom, accounting for over 52% of the total investment.
FIFA says it'll use dynamic pricing for the first phase of 2026 World Cup ticket sales, with seats starting at $60 and prices varying by demand, topping over $6,000 for later rounds. The visa-appreciated draw opens on September 10th for qualified card holders and it runs until September 19th, offering roughly 1 million tickets.
That's the news. I'm Shane Bigger.