Now on the news, I'm Qizhul.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has proposed a global governance initiative at the Shanghai Cooperation Organization Plus meeting in Tianjin.
He said he's looking forward to working with all countries for a more just and equitable global governance system, and advancing toward a community with a shared future for humanity.
Earlier, leaders at the SCO summit released the Tianjin Declaration and approved a new development strategy outlining the organization's goals for the next decade.
The summit marked the launch of four new centers dedicated to combating security threats, transnational crime, cyber threats, and drug trafficking.
The leaders also issued statements commemorating the 80th anniversary of World War II's victory and a founding of the United Nations, and they voiced their support for the multilateral trading system.
The summit adopted 24 outcome documents focusing on enhancing cooperation in security, the economy, cultural ties, and institutional development.
Meanwhile, Kyrgyzstan would take over the groups rotating presidency for 2025-26.
In addition, the Southeast Asian country of Laos has become a new dialogue partner.
While addressing the SCO Council of Heads of State, Chinese President Xi Jinping urged member countries to march toward modernization by working together for a shared future.
As the Chinese saying goes, where will prevails, no boundary holds.
Let us stay true to SCO's founding mission.
Step up to undertake our duties, promote the sound and sustained development of the SCO with greater resolve and more practical measures, and march steadily toward a brighter tomorrow of a community with a shared future for humanity.
He highlighted the Shanghai spirit that emphasized mutual trust, equality, and respect.
President Xi announced that China would provide 2 billion yuan or more than 280 million US dollars in grants to SCO member states this year.
He urged all members to seek common ground and pursue mutual benefit for a better future.
The number of deaths from the earthquake in eastern Afghanistan has risen to over 600.
The Afghan Interior Ministry says the quake has also left more than 1,500 others injured.
Rescue teams are navigating remote areas with limited communication to assess the full extent of the damage and provide aid.
Zmaiali Abasing reports from Afghanistan.
Security and humanitarian sources say the Houthi Group has arrested several employees of the United Nations World Food Programme.
The Houthis are also reportedly holding several staff members of the United Nations Children's Fund in Sana.
Yemeni sources say the group has defying dozens of people on suspicion of collaboration with Israel following an Israeli airstrike that killed the Prime Minister of the Houthi-backed government.
Lebanese parliament speaker Nabi Berry has rejected a US-backed proposal to disarm Hezbollah, saying Lebanon will not give up its weapons under threats.
Berry stressed that discussions over Hezbollah's arms could only take place in the calm and consensual framework under the Constitution.
It is missed attempts by foreign powers to pressure Lebanon into concessions.
France is pushing back against what it calls outside interference in Greenland.
French Foreign Minister Jean-Noel Barrault has visited the Arctic region and described the US maneuvers as disrespectful and unacceptable.
US President Donald Trump has repeatedly expressed interest in controlling Greenland.
Authorities say China's 2025 summer box office has reached nearly 12 billion yuan or almost 1.7 billion US dollars.
The China Film Administration says this past summer saw the release of over 100 films spanning a diverse range of genres, attracting over 320 million moviegoers.
And as for news, I'm Tiju.