Now the news, I'm Do Hongyu.
Chinese President Xi Jinping is in Wurung-chi to attend events marking 70 years of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region.
He's met representatives from all ethnic groups and various sectors.
President Xi extended greetings and encouraged them to work together to build a beautiful Xinjiang in the process of Chinese-style modernization.
The president will attend a celebratory ceremony on Thursday morning.
Xinjiang has prioritized people-centered development over the past seven decades.
More than 70 percent of its public budget goes directly to safeguarding and improving livelihoods, ensuring equal benefits for all ethnic groups.
Compared to 12 years ago, Burkambara disposable income nearly doubled in urban areas and rose by 60 percent in rural areas last year.
The region has reported a completion rate of over 99 percent for nine-year compulsory education, higher than the national average.
Average life expectancy has surged from 30 years in 1949 to 77 years under stronger public health services.
Chinese Premier Li Cheng says the country will not seek any new special and differential treatment in the current and future world trade organization negotiations.
He made the remarks and a high-level meeting on the Global Development Initiative held by China on the sidelines of the general debate to the 80th session of the UN General Assembly.
Premier Li said China will launch another 2,000 livelihood projects in developing countries over the next five years.
He said the country will also carry out 200 marine development cooperation projects during the period to support small island developing states in enhancing their capacity for sustainable development.
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi has held an exchange of views with the U.S. Congressional delegation on strengthening communication and promoting the stable, healthy and sustainable development of bilateral ties.
Wang said the visit by the delegation led by Representative Adam Smith marks the first delegation of U.S. House of Representatives to China since 2019.
He said the visit has opened another window for engagement between the two countries, and that it should be considered an ice-breaking journey.
Wang expressed hope that the visit will help the U.S. understand China accurately, view China objectively, approach differences rationally, engage in friendly interactions, and explore cooperation actively.
He welcomed more members of the U.S. Congress to visit China.
China's state flood control and drought relief headquarters have elevated the typhoon emergency response to level three for Guangdong and Hainan provinces in the face of typhoon Ragasa, the 18th of the year.
Provincial authorities in Guangdong have declared a full emergency and ordered responses on the maximum scale.
Meteorologists warned that the storm is moving rapidly while maintaining strength, making Ragasa the most powerful typhoon to hit China this year.
The densely populated Pearl River Delta and the island province of Hainan have closed schools and businesses, suspended train and ferry services, and reinforced infrastructure.
More than 370,000 people in Guangdong have moved to safer areas.
Chinese authorities have allocated 60,000 disaster relief items, including tents, lighting, and family emergency kits.
The National Commission for Disaster Prevention and Control has dispatched a team to affected areas of Guangdong to assess the situation on the ground and aid local disaster relief efforts.
China Media Group has co-hosted the launch ceremony of the UN&80 campaign with China and the One World Shared Future Global Youth Visual Exhibition with UN agencies in China.
The event highlighted the UN's pivotal role in global affairs, calling for building a more just and equitable global governance system.
CMG President Shen Haisheng delivered a video message reaffirming CMG's commitment to amplifying the UN's voice, covering global governance processes and building bridges between China and the world.
CGTN launched the One World Shared Future Global Youth Visual Challenge in July, receiving over 56,000 submissions from 51 countries.
Entries reflected youth perspectives on key UN sustainable development goals.
15 videos and 20 photos were selected as outstanding works.
And that's the news.
I'm Do Hongyu.