Now the news. I'm Tianyu.
Postal traffic to the United States has plunged more than 80% as a result of Washington's new tariffs. The United Nations Universal Postal Union said 88 global operators have announced the partial or full suspension of mailing services to the U.S.
The Postal Cooperation Agency said it has written to U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio and seeking new solutions. Many operators worldwide have stopped accepting U.S.-bound packages after President Donald Trump announced plans to terminate tax exemptions for small packages.
Local activists estimate that 80% of the residents in Gaza City have chosen not to leave despite Israel's order to move south ahead of an offensive to capture Gaza's largest urban Residents say the south is already overcrowded and they cannot afford transportation.
Israel has announced a humanitarian zone in Hong Yunis that it says will ensure the continued delivery of food, tents, and medicine. Palestinian sources said Israel has been targeting residential towers in Gaza City. The military destroyed two high-rise towers, claiming Hamas used them to monitor Israeli troops. Iranian Foreign Minister Said Abbas Aranji says Tehran and the International Atomic Energy Agency are very close to agreeing on a new framework for the resumption of bilateral cooperation. He also noted that Iran will begin to talk with the United States when Washington is ready for negotiations based on common interests and mutual respect. The two sides were scheduled to hold indirect nuclear negotiations on June 15 in Oman. The talks were suspended after Israel and the US launched air strikes on key Iranian sites.
As a response, the Iranian parliament overwhelmingly passed a law to suspend cooperation with the IAEA.
China had sent its first batch of aid to earthquake hit Afghanistan. The supplies bound for Kabul are worth 50 million yuan or 7 million US dollars. They include tents and blankets.
More will follow in the coming days. The Afghan Red Crescent Society has confirmed over 2,200 fatalities in the tremor that struck the eastern parts of the country.
Air Canada Flight Attendants have overwhelmingly voted against the airline's wage offer.
The Canadian Union of Public Employees said 99% of his members rejected a tentative agreement, which offers a 12% salary increase for most junior flight attendants and an 8% bump for more senior members. Employees staged a three-day strike last month.
Air Canada estimates that it led to flight cancellations for 500,000 customers.
An Ebola outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo has killed at least 15 people.
There are among the 28 people with symptoms since the DRC declared an outbreak on Thursday.
Chris Okamringa has more.
The World Health Organization has warned that infections could rise further.
Neighboring Uganda said it is on high alert and authorities will conduct a risk assessment.
In tennis, Irina Sabalanka defeated local favorite Amanda Anisimova in straight sets to win the US Open.
The Belarusian player took her Grand Slam tally to four after successfully defending her title at Flushing medals. Yannick Sinner and Carlos Ocaraz will play for the men's title.
Xin Zhilai has won the Best Actress Award at the Venus Film Festival for her role in The Sun Rises on us all. The Chinese actress encouraged all girls to chase their dreams in her acceptance speech. The film portrays a tragic romance.
And that's the news. I'm Tianyu.