Now the news.
I'm Wen Jie.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has extended congratulations to the 15th plenary session of the China-Russia Friendship Committee for Peace and Development.
President Xi emphasized the committee has stayed true to its founding mission of promoting friendship and cooperation, served the overall interests of China-Russia relations, and consolidated social and popular support for bilateral ties.
The Chinese leader said he hopes the committee will take this meeting as an opportunity to actively play the role of the main channel for people-to-people exchanges and contribute to mutual understanding and solidarity.
Russian President Vladimir Putin has also extended congratulations to the plenary session.
The 79th session of the United Nations General Assembly has adopted a resolution on strengthening cooperation between the United Nations and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization.
The resolution acknowledges the constructive role of the SCO in ensuring peace and sustainable development, promoting regional cooperation and enhancing good neighborly relations and mutual trust.
It emphasizes the importance of strengthening dialogue, cooperation and coordination between the United Nations system and the SCO.
US President Donald Trump has said he will not attend the G20 summit in South Africa later this year.
However, Trump said he plans to send Vice President JD Vance in his place.
The US President also said the country will host next year's G20 summit at his golf club near Miami.
During his first term in 2019, Trump abandoned a plan to use his golf club as the host site for the G7 summit in 2020.
Having bipartisan criticism that it could benefit him financially and violate the Constitution.
South Korean President Lee Jae-myun has ordered a full response after over 300 Korean workers were arrested in a U.S. immigration raid.
The operation took place at a Hyundai Motor Car Battery Plant in Georgia on Thursday.
South Korean Foreign Minister Cho Hyun said a task force has been formed and he may visit Washington, D.C. if necessary.
More than 470 people were detained in the raid.
The largest single-site enforcement action in U.S. Department of Homeland Security's history.
Europe has launched a supercomputer claimed to be the world's fourth fastest.
German Chancellor Friedrich Merz says the historic project has helped Europe catch up with the U.S. and China, both leading the AI race.
The Jupiter is the region's fastest supercomputer.
Hungary is accusing some European Union member states of secretly purchasing Russian oil.
Hungarian Foreign Minister Peter Zajarto says the country openly buys oil from Russia because it has no alternatives, while some other European countries are importing the same crude through intermediaries at lower prices.
He says the European Union has declined Budapest's request to expand pipeline capacities, while Hungary's southern neighbor Croatia has increased transit fees.
U.S. President Donald Trump has urged European nations to stop importing Russian oil.
The British government has appointed Deville Ami deputy prime minister, following the resignation of Angela Raynor.
He will also serve as Lord Chancellor and Secretary of State for Justice.
America's president, Robert Cooper, will succeed Lamy as foreign secretary.
The reshuffle comes after revelations that Raynor failed to pay 40,000 pounds or nearly 54,000 U.S. daughters in stamp duty on a second home.
International Olympic Committee president, Kirstie Coventry, has announced the creation of four new working groups as part of the Fit for the Future initiative.
The initiative focuses on the Youth Olympic Games, Olympic program, protection of the female category, and commercial partnerships and marketing.
The groups will begin work immediately to address key challenges facing the Olympic movement.
The initiative represents the first structural change implemented under Coventry's leadership since her election in March 2025.
Coventry is the first woman and the first African to lead the IOC in its 131-year history.
And that's the news.
I'm Wenzhi.