Now the news. I'm Shane Begum.
China's marked victory day with a series of events highlighted by a major military parade in central Beijing.
The events marked the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese people's war of resistance against Japanese aggression and the world anti-fascist war.
Around 50,000 people gathered at Tianmen Square Wednesday morning for the military parade.
Before reviewing the troops, Chinese President Xi Jinping addressed the gathering and stressed the pivotal role that China played in the global fight against fascism.
The Chinese people's war of resistance against the Japanese aggression was an important part of the world anti-fascist war.
With huge national sacrifice, the Chinese people made major contributions to saving human civilization and safeguarding world peace.
President Xi pledged that China will remain committed to the path of peaceful development and work with all peoples around the world in building a community with a shared future for humanity.
He emphasized a correct view of World War II.
History cautioned us that humanity rises and falls together.
Only when our countries and nations treat each other as equals, coexist in peace and support each other, can we uphold common security, eradicate the root cause of war, and prevent the reoccurrence of historical tragedies.
China's military demonstrated its combat capabilities and unveiled new weapons during the parade.
Later in the day, President Xi hosted a reception for visiting world leaders at the Great Hall of the People, addressing the reception the Chinese president called on all countries to safeguard international fairness and justice, follow a path of peaceful development and strive for the people's well-being.
On Wednesday evening, President Xi and other Chinese leaders, along with war veterans and merit and honor recipients, attended a gala-themed justice prevails.
President Xi has held bilateral talks with the visiting leaders.
In a meeting with his Indonesian counterpart, Prabowo Subianto, Xi Jinping urged the two countries to expand opening up, as well as cooperation in critical minerals, the digital economy, and artificial intelligence.
Ahead of the commemorative events, the Chinese leader also spoke with guests including the presidents of Russia, Mongolia, and Iran, and the prime ministers of Pakistan and Malaysia.
After watching the V-date military parade, Tong Ho Lam from Macau shared her thoughts on the event, the future, and Macau's role as a bridge to the world.
I am grateful to be a Macau Gen Z. Macau has fully leveraged its role as the national window, creating more opportunities for every young individual.
Hong Kong entrepreneur Lee Pak Hong expressed his pride, emphasizing that the people of China are united and younger generations in Hong Kong should cherish peace.
Our country has always given Hong Kong very great support. Now we must remember the history and keep to learn from 5,000 years of the Chinese, Chinese culture.
A private sector survey shows China's services activity grew at its fastest pace in 15 months in August, driven by stronger domestic demand and a rebound in export orders.
Rating dogs, General Services PMI rose to 53, the highest since May of last year. The uptick aligns with the official PMI, though Rating Dogs Index captures smaller export-focused firms along the coast.
New businesses rose at the fastest rate in 15 months, and new export orders grew the most since February 8, buoyed by tourism.
Thailand's acting Prime Minister says his caretaker government is moved to dissolve the lower house of parliament, potentially leading to an early general election.
Pum Thamwee Chea Chai said restoring political stability is essential to prevent further economic decline. Stressing that returning decision-making authority to the electorate is the appropriate course of action.
Thailand's ruling Poo Thai Party has lost its majority in the lower house and is struggling to form a new government following a constitutional court ruling that removed Phaetong Tung Suna Watt from her premiership.
The main opposition People's Party has decided to back the Pum Chai Thai Party candidate as the next Prime Minister.
The United Nations interim force in Lebanon says Israeli drones dropped four grenades near its peacekeepers, calling it one of Israel's most serious violations since last year's ceasefire.
Unifil's called the strike a violation of international law. The attack came days after the Security Council voted to end Unifil's mandate in 2027, after nearly five decades in Lebanon.
That's the news. I'm Shane Begum.