Now the news, I'm Do Hongyu.
China has marked Victory Day with a series of events, highlighted by a major military parade in central Beijing.
The events marked the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
Around 50,000 people gathered in Tiananmen Square Wednesday morning for the military parade.
Before reviewing the troops, Chinese President Xi Jinping addressed the gathering and stressed the pivotal role China played in the global fight against fascism.
The Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression was an important part of the World Anti-Fascist War.
With huge national sacrifice, the Chinese people made major contributions to saving human civilization and safeguarding world peace.
President Xi pledged that China will remain committed to the path of peaceful development and work with all people around the world in building a community with a shared future for humanity.
He emphasized the correct view of World War II.
China's military demonstrated its combat capabilities and unveiled new weapons during the parade.
On Wednesday evening, President Xi and other Chinese leaders, along with war veterans and merit and honor recipients, attended a gala-themed Justice Prevails.
The chair of the Central Military Commission also signed an order to commend all personnel who participated in the military parade.
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi says the friendship between China and Hungary sets an example for China and Europe to enhance mutual trust and expand cooperation.
He made the remarks while meeting with his Hungarian counterpart Peter Siatou in Beijing.
Siatou attended commemorations marking the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War on Wednesday.
Wang Yi said China-Hungary relations are at their best in history, and that the successful bilateral cooperation demonstrates that China and Europe are partners instead of rivals.
Siatou said Hungary looks forward to further deepening relations with China.
He said cooperation between Europe and China brings about opportunities rather than risks, and regarding China as a systemic rival is the biggest misjudgment.
Siatou also said his country is willing to play a constructive role in promoting the development of Europe-China ties.
Israel has rejected Hamas' proposal for reaching a ceasefire deal in Gaza to end the ongoing conflict.
It says its army will continue to prepare for a major attack on Gaza City.
Hamas announced on Wednesday that it's ready for the deal, including a prisoner for hostage swap.
It created a willingness to reach the deal under which Israeli hostilities in Gaza will be released in exchange for an agreed number of Palestinian prisoners held in Israel.
The deal also includes a permanent ceasefire, the withdrawal of Israeli forces from Gaza, the reopening of border crossings to allow the delivery of humanitarian aid and essential supplies and the start of reconstruction efforts.
Hamas also voiced support for establishing an independent national administration composed of technocrats to take immediate responsibility for managing Gaza's civil affairs.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu dismissed Hamas' statement as a spin.
He said Israel will only agree to end the war if Hamas accepts full Israeli security control over Gaza, the demilitarization of Hamas and Gaza, the establishment of a non-Palestinian administration and the release of all hostilities.
A new round of deadly floods in North India has killed five more people.
Swollen rivers have breached banks in multiple provinces.
About 10,000 people along a river in New Delhi have been forced to evacuate.
The monsoon season has seen nearly 900 people killed in India since late June.
More stormy weather is expected.
Wildfires are forcing evacuations near a piece of Chinese history in northern California.
Flames are rapidly spreading across the Gold Rush town of Chinese camp known for its Chinese immigrant population during the mid-19th century.
The fire has caused extensive damage.
Officials say the fires were likely sparked by lightning.
And that's the news.
I'm Dohung Yu.