Now the news, I'm Tianyu.
U.S. President Donald Trump had signed an executive order to rename the Department of Defense the Department of War.
That was the title it held until after World War II when officials sought to emphasize the Pentagon's role in preventing conflict.
Trump has also challenged conventional norms over domestic deployment of military, deploying troops in cities like Los Angeles and Washington.
A White House fact sheet shows that the order will authorize Defense Secretary Pete Hexeth and subordinate officials to use secondary titles such as Secretary of War in official correspondence.
Nick Harper reports from Washington.
The U.S. president still needs Congress to approve this name change.
But importantly for the U.S. president, he's looking at what it was called during the First and Second World War and it was still called the Department of War then.
He has said that the U.S. had an unbelievable history of victory when it was called the Department of War.
So partly due to that nostalgia but I think also partly due to the desire amongst the Trump administration to shake things up.
Official data shows that China's service trade posted solid growth in the first seven months of 2025.
The Commerce Ministry says the country saw a steep increase in the trade of travel-related services.
The volume of trading services reached nearly 4.6 trillion yuan or over 644 billion U.S.
dollars between January and July and an increase of 8.2%.
Russian President Vladimir Putin had said the country will roll out a visa-free policy for Chinese citizens to reciprocate a similar policy from China.
The president was speaking at the Eastern Economic Forum in Russia's Far East.
Putin said the policy reflects friendship between the two countries and it will further promote people-to-people exchanges and facilitate business and trade activities.
China has rolled out a one-year visa-free policy for Russian citizens with ordinary passports.
The policy takes effect from September 15.
The Chinese embassy in Afghanistan has handed over 200,000 U.S. dollars in emergency humanitarian cash assistance to support Afghanistan's earthquake relief efforts.
The Red Cross Society of China provided the assistance.
The handover took place during a meeting between a senior diplomat from the Chinese embassy and the president of the Afghan Red Crescent Society.
Earlier, the Chinese government said it will provide 50 million yuan or roughly 7 million U.S. dollars in emergency humanitarian aid for quick-hit Afghanistan.
According to the Afghan Red Crescent Society, the powerful quick has killed more than 2,200 people and injured more than 3,600 others.
The British government has appointed David Lamy, deputy prime minister, following the resignation of Angela Reiner.
He will also serve as Lord Chancellor and Secretary of State for justice.
Yavit Cooper will succeed Lamy as foreign secretary.
The reshuffle came after revelations that Reiner failed to pay 40,000 pounds or nearly 5,400 U.S. dollars in stamp duty on a second home.
French President Emmanuel Macron has announced that 26 countries, mostly from Europe, have formally vowed to deploy troops as part of a future Russian-Ukrainian ceasefire.
The announcement followed a virtual meeting of the Coalition of the Willing co-chaired by Macron and British Prime Minister Kirstjen Stammer.
Macron said the countries will contribute to a reassurance force that could deploy troops in Ukraine to provide support.
He also said the participants have held a call with U.S. President Donald Trump and the U.S. is set to finalize its contributions to the security guarantees in the coming days.
The World Health Organization says the spread of MPOCs in Africa no longer represents a public health emergency of international concern.
WHO Director General Tejriz Atnam-Gabrielsis said the decision is based on sustained declines in cases and deaths in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and in other affected countries, including Burundi and Sierra Leone.
The health body stated that lifting the emergency declaration does not mean the threat is over and MPOCs remains a continental emergency.
More than 100 countries worldwide have reported cases since May 2022.
That's the news.
I'm Ken You.