Now the news, I'm Do Hongyu.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has unveiled a new initiative aimed at creating a more inclusive international order.
President Xi used his address and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization Plus meeting in Tianjin to launch the Global Governance Initiative.
He urged member states to lead the way in shaping a fairer world order, which is based on such guiding principles and sovereign equality, international law and multilateralism.
We should adhere to sovereign equality.
We should maintain that all countries, regardless of size, strength and wealth, are equal participants, decision makers and beneficiaries in global governance.
We should promote greater democracy in international relations and increase the representation and voice of developing countries.
The Chinese president also announced a series of new platforms for China-SCO cooperation, including partnerships in energy, green industry and the digital economy, along with centers for scientific innovation, higher education and vocational training.
He pledged to expand the region's renewable energy capacity and proposed deeper collaboration in artificial intelligence, satellite navigation and lunar exploration.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has urged member countries of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization to march toward modernization by working together for a shared future.
In his keynote speech on the SEO Council of Hezhar State in Tianjin, President Xi highlighted the Shanghai spirit that emphasizes mutual trust, equality and respect.
He urged all members to seek common ground and pursue mutual benefit for a better future.
The Shanghai Cooperation Organization has grown into the world's largest regional organization with a participation of 26 countries and a combined economic output of nearly $30 trillion.
Leaders on the summit have released the Tianjin Declaration.
They also approved a new development strategy outlining the SEO's goals for the next decade.
The summit marked the launch of four new centers dedicated to combating security threats, transnational crimes, cyber threats and drug trafficking.
The leaders also issued statements commemorating the 80th anniversary of victory in World War II and the founding of the United Nations and devoid their support for the multilateral trading system.
The summit adopted 24 outcome documents focusing on enhancing cooperation in security, the economy, cultural ties and institutional development.
The Shenzhen Hong Kong Guangzhou Innovation Cluster in southern China has taken the top ranking among the world's 100 leading innovation clusters.
The World Intellectual Property Organization has released the 2025 Global Innovation Index.
This is the first time the cluster has surpassed the Tokyo Yokohama cluster in Japan to become the world's leading innovation hub.
Officials say the number of deaths from a powerful earthquake in eastern Afghanistan has exceeded 800.
A spokesperson for the Afghan government also says the quake has left more than 2,800 others injured.
Rescue teams are navigating remote areas with limited communication to assess the full extent of the damage and provide aid.
Former Czech Prime Minister Andrei Babish says he's canceled his election campaign for Tuesday after being attacked during a rally.
Babish, the leader of the opposition ANO party, was struck in the head with a metallic forum crutch by a man during an election rally on Monday afternoon.
Czech police said officers detained the man after the attack in the eastern town of Dubra.
The Czech Republic is set to hold elections to the lower house of the parliament in early October.
A senior EU official says the European Union will continue to enforce its digital rules despite U.S. criticism.
European Commission Executive Vice President Hannah Vierkunen said the rules apply equally to all companies providing services in the EU.
U.S. President Donald Trump warned on Tuesday that his country would impose substantial additional tariffs and export restrictions on countries that adopt digital taxes or regulations targeting U.S. tech giants.
And that's the news.
I'm Do Hongyu.