Now, the news.
I'm Wenzhi.
The top leaders of China and North Korea have reaffirmed their friendship and vowed to further develop bilateral relations.
The messages came as Chinese President Xi Jinping held talks with North Korean top leader Kim Jong-un in Beijing.
Kim attended commemorations marking the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese people's war of resistance against Japanese aggression and the world anti-fascist war.
President Xi said the move demonstrated North Korea's firm resolve to safeguard the outcomes of the victory in World War II.
He also said China is willing to strengthen high-level exchanges and strategic communication and enhance mutual understanding and friendship with North Korea.
President Xi added that China has always maintained an objective and impartial stance regarding the Korean Peninsula issue, and it stands ready to continue strengthening coordination with North Korea to strive to maintain peace and stability.
Kim said the friendship between North Korea and China will remain unchanged no matter how the international landscape evolves.
He said his country is willing to work with China to strengthen exchanges and conduct experience sharing, and that North Korea is ready to deepen economic and trade cooperation with China.
China has decided to provide humanitarian supplies of 50 million yuan or around 7 million US dollars to quick-hit Afghanistan.
The China International Development Cooperation Agency says the supplies include tents, blankets and food.
According to the Afghan Red Crescent Society, the powerful quick has killed more than 2,200 people and injured more than 3,600 others.
Many parts of China are on alert for mountain torrents as heavy downpours are set to lash parts of the country through Friday.
Authorities have warned the risk of mountain torrents in Shanxi and Gansu provinces in the country's northwest, as well as Sichuan province in the southwest.
Local authorities have been urged to strengthen real-time monitoring, issue timely flood alerts, and implement preventative measures to mitigate risks.
Washington DC has filed a lawsuit against the Trump administration over the deployment of National Guard troops in the US capital.
The district's attorney general said such deployment is unlawful, and that the forced military occupation of the District of Columbia violates local autonomy and basic freedoms, which must end.
The attorney general's office said the deployment violates the Home Rule Act, which grants a local government the authority to govern itself, exercising powers of governance within its own administrative area.
The lawsuit was filed less than a month after US President Donald Trump signed an executive order on deploying the National Guard to the US capital to help restore law and order and ensure public safety.
All for nuclear in Lisbon have been suspended for technical inspections, following a deadly accident that killed 17 people and injured 21 others.
The accident happened when the glory of a nuclear, one of the best-known tourist attractions in the Portuguese capital, derailed and overturned.
The Portuguese government declared Thursday a national day of mourning, while the Lisbon City Council announced a three-day city-wide mourning period.
Mayor Carlos Moedas said he expects an overall investigation.
The city needs answers.
On behalf of the people of Lisbon, I am the first person to want everything to be investigated.
I asked the president of Caris Lisbon's tramways company to start an internal investigation, but also an external, independent investigation to look at all the responsibilities as soon as possible.
Authorities said they have identified most of the injured.
Portugal's civil protection head Margarida Castro-Martins said foreign nationals are among the dead.
Of the victims, we have identified seven men and eight women, all adults, including foreign nationals.
We do not yet have information on the age or the nationality of these victims.
That is the responsibility of the public prosecutor's office.
The Chinese embassy said no Chinese nationals have been confirmed among the victims so far.
And that's the news.
I'm Wenzhi.