Now the news. I'm Shane Begum, Chinese President Xi Jinping says the rejuvenation of the Chinese nation is unstoppable and is addressed to the grand gathering that marks the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the world anti-fascist war. The president highlighted China's contribution to the fight against fascism. He also pledged that China will remain committed to the path of peaceful development and work with people around the world to build a community with a shared future for humanity. President Xi urged all Chinese people to follow the thoughts on socialism with Chinese characteristics for the new era.
We should stay firmly on the path of socialism with Chinese characteristics and carry forward the great spirit of the War of Resistance. We should press the head with enterprise and resolve and advance the unity, the cause of building China into a great country on all fronts and realizing great national rejuvenation through China's modernization.
Leaders from many countries including Russian President Vladimir Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong-un attended the commemorative event that included a military parade at Tiananmen's Square in downtown Beijing. China's military demonstrated its combat capabilities and unveiled many new weapons. Later in the day, President Xi hosted a reception for visiting world leaders at the Great Hall of the People. Addressing the reception, the Chinese leader called on all countries to safeguard international fairness and justice, follow a path of peaceful development, and strive for the people's well-being. He said China will remain a force for peace, stability, and development and hopes the world will work together to advance global modernization.
A private sector survey shows China's services activity grew at its fastest pace in 15 months in August driven by stronger domestic demand and a rebound in export orders. Rating dogs, global services PMI rose to 53, the highest since May of last year. The uptick aligns with the official PMI, though Rating Dogs Index captures smaller export-focused firms along the coast. New businesses rose at the fastest rate in 15 months, and new export orders grew the most since February 8, buoyed by tourism.
Thailand's acting prime minister says his caretaker government has moved to dissolve the lower house of parliament, potentially leading to an early general election. Pum Tamwee Cheh-Hai said restoring political stability is essential to prevent further economic decline.
Stressing that returning decision-making authority to the electorate is the appropriate course of action. Thailand's ruling Poo Tai Party has lost its majority in the lower house and is struggling to form a new government following a constitutional court ruling that removed Phaetong Tan-Sirnawat from her primership. The main opposition people's party has decided to back the Boom Chai Tai Party candidate as the next prime minister.
Deputy Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu says Israel is entering the decisive stage of the war in Gaza. He made the announcement as he was seeking to rally support among reservists and counter reports of low turnout for the latest call-up. Israel has summoned around 40,000 reservists as part of its plan to capture Gaza City, the largest single call-up since the war began nearly two years ago. Pumeteer reports said the turnout was lower than expected.
In a letter, over 350 reservists also announced they would refuse to serve if ordered into Gaza, denouncing the government's decision to take over Gaza City as reckless and vowing not to take part.
A U.S. federal judge has ruled that the Trump administration violated a 19th century law when it deployed National Guard troops and Marines to Los Angeles in June to quell protests against federal immigration raids. The ruling said the Trump administration violated the Posse-Komitatus Act that prohibits the use of the U.S. military to execute domestic law without approval from Congress. It bars the Trump administration from deploying, ordering, instructing, training, or using the National Guard deployed in California and any military troops deployed in the state to execute the laws. The White House said that once again a rogue judge is trying to usurp the authority of the commander-in-chief to protect American cities from violence and destruction.
A suicide car bomb has struck the headquarters of one of Libya's most powerful military units in the town of Bonnet-Waleed, about 170 kilometers southeast of Tripoli. The 444th Combat Brigade said an attacker detonated a vehicle packed with explosives outside the headquarters. The unit released images showing damaged buildings and debris scattered across the site. The brigade's operating under the U.N. recognized government of National Unity in Tripoli. In recent days, armed groups have mobilized near Tripoli following reports of sporadic clashes.
On Tuesday, the United Nations support mission in Libya said it was gravely alarmed by the escalating military buildup warning it could spark a new round of fighting.
In Vast the News, I'm Shane Begum.