Now, the news. I'm Tian Lü.
Chinese and U.S. delegations have wrapped up the first day of talks on economic and trade issues in Spain. Issues on the agenda also include Washington's unilateral tariff measures, the abuse of export controls and TikTok. The Chinese delegation, headed by vice premier Jolie Fohn, will be in Spain from Sunday to Wednesday. Ken Brown reports from Madrid.
Interestingly, he said that it was the top representatives, people like Jolie Fohn, the Chinese vice premier and Scott Besin, the U.S. Treasury Secretary, that they were finished for the day. But that technical teams are going to continue working through the night. It kind of gives you an idea of the scale of the detail, the scale of the task at hand here to come to some kind of trade agreement between the world's two largest economies.
His foreign minister Wang Yi says China's development will provide opportunities for all countries in the world, including Slovenia. He made the remarks during a meeting with Slovenian National Council President Marco Lodruk. Wang Yi said China is willing to expand cooperation with Slovenia, jointly upholding the international system with the UN at its core and play a constructive role in settling global disputes in the political manner. He also expressed the hope that Slovenia firmly sticks to the One China Principle and plays a positive role in promoting the sound and stable development of China-Europe ties. Lodruk said the Slovenian National Council is willing to work with the Chinese legislative bodies to enhance mutual learning and communication and play a bigger role in promoting bilateral cooperation in areas such as trade and economy, investment, culture, science and technology, education and sports. He also welcomed the Global Governance Initiative proposed by Chinese President Xi Jinping.
Hamats says it has suspended talks on the prisoner swap with Israel after recusing Israel of targeting its negotiating delegation in Qatar last week. A senior Hamats official said negotiations cannot continue if the delegation responsible for them is attacked inside a country acting as mediator. He accused the Israeli Prime Minister of obstructing efforts to reach a ceasefire and a prisoner exchange. He also warned that intensified Israeli strikes on residential towers in Gaza could endanger Israeli captives. The official also dismissed the US Secretary of State Marco Rubio's visit to Israel, seeing Hamats expected no change in Israel's position. Israeli airstrikes have levelled residential buildings in Gaza City in recent days, killing dozens. Israel says its operations target Hamats infrastructure and fighters, while Palestinians say civilians are bearing the brunt of the attacks.
Yemen's Houthi group says 26 staff members of local media outlets were among 46 people killed in Israeli airstrikes in Sana'a on Wednesday. It says the strikes destroyed the officers of two newspapers, adding that the attacks will not weaken its media operations.
The Israeli military has described the strikes as a response to drone and missile attacks launched by the Houthi group.
A US diplomat has expressed regret over a recent immigration raid in a country that detained more than 300 South Korean workers. US Deputy Secretary of State Christopher Landl met South Korean First Vice Foreign Minister Park Yong-joo in Seoul. Park urged Landl to advance bilateral discussions on follow-up measures which could include creating a new visa category.
In sports, Chinese patlers Sun Yingsha and Wang Chuchun have clinched the singles titles at the World Table Tennis Champions Macau 2025. World No. 1 Sun defended a crown with a 4-3 win over World No. 2 and teammate Wang Man-yu in the women's final. Wang Chuchun eased the past Brazil's Hugo Calderano for no in the men's final.
And that's the news. I'm Tien Lu.