Now, the news.
I'm Qizhi.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has arrived in Rumorchi to attend celebratory events marking 70 years of Xinjiang Weigou Autonomous Region.
He has met representatives from all local government levels and across various sectors.
President Xi extended greetings and encouraged him to work together to build a beautiful Xinjiang in the process of Chinese-style modernization.
Xinjiang has prioritized people-centered development over the past seven decades.
More than 70% of its public budget goes directly to safeguarding and improving livelihoods, ensuring equal benefits of all ethnic groups.
Compared to 12 years ago, per capita disposable income nearly doubled in urban areas and rose by 60% in rural areas last year.
The region has reported a completion rate of over 99% for nine-year compulsory education higher than the national average.
Average life expectancy has surged from 30 years in 1949 to 77 years under stronger public health services.
Provincial authorities in Guangdong have declared a full emergency status and ordered responses on the maximum scale in the face of typhoon regal.
Many cities have suspended schools on transportation.
The super typhoon is moving toward southern China and is projected to land on Wednesday.
Mereng environment forecasters have issued the highest alert for storm surges and waves.
The provincial capital in Hainan has also closed schools, parks and construction sites in anticipation of destructive rains and winds.
The Hong Kong-Zhu Hai-Makhal Bridge is temporarily shut.
Before regasser made his way toward China had slammed into the northern Philippines, killing at least three people and injuring several others.
The Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development has lifted his forecast for global economic growth this year to 3.2%.
That's 0.3 points higher than its report from June.
The new OECD Economic Outlook interim report expects China's economy to grow 4.9%, up from the 4.7% prediction in June.
It said U.S. economic growth was slow to 1.8% within the year.
The Organization also kept his 2.9% expansion forecast for the world next year unchanged.
The head of the United Nations nuclear agency says diplomatic efforts to reach an agreement over Iran's nuclear program are at a difficult juncture.
International Atomic Energy Agency director General Rafael Grossi held a meeting with Iranian Foreign Minister Abbas Araqi in New York.
Araqi urged Western countries to curb their excessive demands and stop misusing the UN Security Council to exert pressure on Iran.
The Security Council voted to reimpose UN sanctions on Iran last week.
The measures are set to take effect on Sunday.
The United Nations Development Programme says Vietnam could lose up to US$25 billion in exports because of tariffs, making it the hardest hit country in Southeast Asia.
That equals nearly one-fifth of the country's annual total.
Since the tariffs took effect last month, Vietnam has already seen a 5.5% drop in footwear shipments, a sector that accounts for a significant portion of its economy.
The World Bank has downgraded Vietnam's growth forecast for the coming year.
UN Humanitarians have reported a sharp deterioration in the humanitarian situation in the capital of North Darfur in Sudan.
According to the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs, deadly attacks and fresh displacement compound the suffering of civilians, and the violence continues to have a devastating impact on humanitarian response efforts.
The International Organization for Migration says about 7,500 people fled the Abu Shuk displacement camp last week on the outskirts of Al-Farsha and the parts of the town itself amid heightened insecurity.
The UN Under-Secretary-General for Humanitarian Affairs and the Emergency Relief Coordinator called from end to the fighting between the rapid support forces and the Sudanese armed forces, stressing the need to protect civilians and to allow aid in.
In Asuna News, I'm Tijir.