Now the news, I'm Do Hongyu.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has held talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin in Beijing.
Earlier, President Xi joined President Putin and Mongolian President Ufna Hursuk for a trilateral meeting in the Chinese capital.
Putin and Hursuk are in Beijing to attend events commemorating the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
On Tuesday morning, President Xi also held separate meetings with the Mongolian President Pakistani Prime Minister Shaba Sharif and Uspec President Shafkat Mirza Youyev.
The leaders all took part in the just-concluded Shanghai Cooperation Organization Summit in Tianjin.
There will be among dozens of foreign leaders attending China's Victory Day commemorations on Wednesday.
Chinese President Xi Jinping has unveiled a new initiative aimed at creating a more inclusive international order.
President Xi used his address and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization Plus meeting in Tianjin to launch the Global Governance Initiative.
He urged member states to lead the way in shaping a fairer world order, which is based on such guiding principles and sovereign equality, international law and multilateralism.
We should adhere to sovereign equality.
We should maintain that all countries, regardless of size, strength and wealth, are equal participants, decision makers and beneficiaries in global governance.
We should promote greater democracy in international relations and increase the representation and voice of developing countries.
The Chinese President also announced a series of new platforms for China-SCO cooperation, including partnerships in energy, green industry and the digital economy, along with centers for scientific innovation, higher education and vocational training.
He pledged to work with other SEO countries to expand renewable energy capacity and propose deeper collaboration in artificial intelligence, satellite navigation and lunar exploration.
Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi has highlighted a series of outcomes achieved in the Shanghai Cooperation Organization's summit in Tianjin.
The summit approved a development strategy for the SEO in the 2026-35 period.
Wang said the strategy set the tone and direction for the organization's growth in the next decade.
The summit issued a statement defending the victorious outcomes of World War II.
The SEO also expressed firm support for the multilateral trading system.
The event inaugurated four new centers on countering security threats, tackling transnational organized crimes, improving information security and strengthening anti-drug cooperation.
The member states also made a decision to establish an SEO development bank.
The summit accepted Laos as a partner to make the SEO a 27-nation family.
Former Czech Prime Minister Andrei Babish says he's canceled his election campaign for Tuesday after being attacked during a rally.
Babish, the leader of the opposition-ANO party, was struck in the head with a metallic forearm crutch by a man during an election rally on Monday afternoon.
Czech police said officers detained the man after the attack in the eastern town of Dubra.
The Czech Republic is set to hold elections to the lower house of the parliament in early October.
A senior EU official says the European Union will continue to enforce its digital rules despite U.S. criticism.
European Commission Executive Vice President Hannah Vierkunen said the rules apply equally to all companies providing services in the EU.
U.S. President Donald Trump warned on Tuesday that his country would impose substantial additional tariffs and export restrictions on countries that adopt digital taxes or regulations targeting U.S. tech giants.
Jordan says its field hospital in Southern Gaza has fitted over 580 prosthetic limbs for amputees since its deployment.
The Jordan Armed Forces said the initiative aims to ease the suffering of amputees and help them return to daily life.
The hospital said each fitting takes about an hour and is provided free of charge.
Jordan dispatched two field hospitals to northern and southern Gaza in September 2024.
And that's the news.
I'm Do-Hung Yu.