Now the news. I'm Shane Bigum. Chinese President Xi Jinping has expressed the country's readiness to conduct cooperation with all countries in artificial intelligence to boost its development and ensure its outcomes better benefit the people. He made the remarks in a congratulatory letter to the World Smart Industry Expo 2025. President Xi said China will further advance the integration between scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation in the AI sector and use it to empower high quality social and economic development.
Russian President Vladimir Putin has said the country will roll out a visa free policy for Chinese citizens to reciprocate similar policies from China. The president was speaking at the Eastern Economic Forum in Russia's Far East. Putin said the policy reflects friendship between the two countries and it'll further promote people to people exchanges and facilitate business and trade activities. China's rolled out a one year visa free policy for Russian citizens with ordinary passports. The policy takes effect from September 15th.
UN Secretary General Antony Guterres has welcomed the Global Governance Initiative proposed by China. He emphasized the initiative's grounding in multilateralism and the importance of strengthening the international system with the UN at its core.
Portuguese Prime Minister Luís Montenegro will visit China from Monday to Wednesday.
The official visit comes at the invitation of Chinese Premier Li Cheng. The Chinese Foreign Ministry has called for joint efforts with Portugal to promote strategic mutual trust, deep and friendly exchanges, advance high quality Belt and Road cooperation and enrich their partnership.
Official data shows that China's service trade posted solid growth in the first seven months of 2025. The Commerce Ministry says the country saw a steep increase in the trade of travel related services. The volume of trade and services reached nearly 4.6 trillion yuan, or over 644 billion US dollars between January and July, an increase of 8.2%.
China's allocated 940 million yuan, roughly 132 million US dollars, in disaster relief funds to support flood hit regions. The Finance Ministry says part of the money will go to four provincial level regions, including Fujian, Guangdong, Xinjiang and Gansu, to assist with crop replanting and repairs of damaged farming facilities. Meanwhile, eight provincial level regions, including Beijing, Hubei and Mongolia and Jilin, receive funding to accelerate repairs on flood damaged water conservancy projects.
Police say at least 15 people have died in a bus accident in southern Sri Lanka. Over a dozen others suffered injuries with several in critical condition. The bus carrying a group of municipal employees was reportedly returning from a leisure trip when the disaster happened on Thursday night. The vehicle veered off the road and plunged down a ravine several hundred meters deep. Rescue operations have already concluded and police are investigating the cause of the accident.
French President Emmanuel Macron's announced that 26 countries, mostly from Europe, have formally vowed to deploy troops as part of a future Russian-Ukrainian ceasefire. The announcement followed a virtual meeting of the Coalition of the Willing, co-chaired by Macron and British Prime Minister Kier Starrer. Macron said the country is still contributing to a reassurance force that could deploy troops in Ukraine to provide support.
He also said the participants have held a call with US President Donald Trump and the US is set to finalize its contributions to the security guarantees in the coming days.
Ukrainian President Vladimir Zelensky welcomed the announcement saying a meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin is necessary for advancing peace efforts. A Kremlin spokesperson said foreign military units cannot provide security guarantees to Ukraine. Ross Cullen has more from Paris.
It is complicated because the European allies of Ukraine do see it as crucial. It is also something that Vladimir Zelensky has said himself. There has to be US backstop, there has to be US participation in the security guarantees, involvement in the design and the architecture of those security guarantees. There has been wavering signals from the US.
We heard Donald Trump saying he wasn't ruling out US boots on the ground. Then he was ruling it out. He was saying there could be air support without defining if that would be jets and bombers or if that would simply be air defense systems.
Washington D.C.'s filed a lawsuit against the Trump administration over the deployment of National Guard troops in the US capital. The district's attorney general called deployment unlawful and said that the forced military occupation of the District of Columbia violates local autonomy and basic freedoms. The attorney general's office said the deployment violates the Home Rule Act which grants the local government the authority to govern itself, exercising powers of governance within its own administrative area.
In Vast the News, I'm Shane Degas.