Now the news, I'm Do Hongyu.
China will stage a military parade on Wednesday to mark the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
China Media Group says the parade will feature 45 formations and aerial echelons.
The viewing stands and Tiananmen Square are arranged to form Chinese characters, symbolizing the people and their collective strength.
In the center, 14 doves represent China's 14 years of total resistance against Japanese aggression.
China's war of resistance fought from 1931 to 1945, was among the longest and bloodiest chapters of World War II, and the invitation of Chinese President Xi Jinping, leaders of multiple countries, and arrived in Beijing to attend the commemoration.
China and Russia have signed more than 20 cooperation agreements in areas including energy, aerospace, and artificial intelligence, as President Xi Jinping held talks with President Vladimir Putin in Beijing.
The Russian leader is in China to attend the Shanghai Cooperation Organization Summit and commemorations of the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
The leaders of China, Russia, and Mongolia had a three-way meeting where President Xi proposed deeper trust and cooperation.
In his separate talks with Mongolian President Ufna Hurasuk, Xi Jinping called on both sides to take the building of a community with a shared future as the guiding principle.
President Xi also held talks with more world leaders ahead of the V-day events.
He told his U.S. back counterpart that China's willing to strengthen cooperation in joint scientific research, green energy, and more.
While speaking with President Sardar Berdimov-Hamedov of Turkmenistan, President Xi said cooperation is based on mutual trust and mutual benefit, and the two countries can complement each other.
In his meeting with Iranian President Masoud Pazashkian, the Chinese leader said China respects Iran's right to the peaceful use of nuclear power and supports Tehran in defending its interests through negotiations.
President Xi spoke with Pakistani Prime Minister Sheba Sharif, saying a strong bilateral relationship is conducive to safeguarding regional peace and development.
While speaking with Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim, President Xi called on the two countries to deepen strategic coordination and multilateral cooperation to build a stronger China-Asian community with a shared future.
China's top political adviser has called the victory in the war of resistance against Japanese aggression and the world anti-fascist war a great achievement to follow Chinese people, including compatriots from Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, and overseas.
Chairman Wang Huening of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference National Committee attended a symposium in Beijing.
He stressed the importance of promoting China's national spirit and the spirit of resistance, and working together to advance Chinese modernization and realize national rejuvenation.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu says Israel is entering the decisive stage of the war in Gaza.
He made the announcement as he was seeking to rally support among reservists and counter reports of low turnout for the latest call-up.
Netanyahu said the military campaign has advanced Israel toward a sweeping victory.
Israel has summoned about 40,000 reservists as part of its plan to capture Gaza City, the largest single call-up since the war began nearly two years ago.
But media reports said the turnout was lower than expected.
More than 350 reservists also announced in a letter that they will refuse to serve if ordered into Gaza, denouncing the government's decision to take over Gaza City as reckless and vowing not to take part.
A suicide car bomb has targeted the headquarters of Libya's 444th combat brigade in Bani Walid.
The brigade said in a statement that a suicide tanker detonated himself inside a car in front of the headquarters.
It said the situation is under control and that the headquarters continues to perform its duties.
The 444th combat brigade is one of the military units affiliated with the Libyan army in the western region under the authority of the UN-recognized government of National Unity based in Tripoli.
And that's the news.
I'm Dohoon.