Now the news, An Do Hong Yu.
Chinese President Xi Jinping says the country will remain committed to the path of peaceful development and work with all people around the world in building a community with a shared future for humanity.
He made the remarks in his speech and a grand gathering in Beijing, marking the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
Xi warned that humanity today again has to choose between peace and war, dialogue and confrontation, win-win cooperation, and zero-sum game.
History cautions us that humanity rises and falls together.
Only when all countries and nations treat each other as equals, coexist in peace and support each other can we uphold common security, eradicate the root cause of war, and prevent the reoccurrence of historical tragedies.
The grand gathering includes a military parade featuring 45 formations and aerial echelons, and showcasing both traditional battle forces and new domain forces with new combat capabilities.
President Xi has reviewed the troops during the parade.
And the invitation of the Chinese president, leaders of multiple countries, including Russian president Vladimir Putin and North Korean leader Kim Jong-un, are also attending the gathering.
China's war of resistance, fought from 1931 to 1945, was among the longest and bloodiest chapters of World War II.
China and Russia have signed more than 20 cooperation agreements in areas including energy, aerospace, and artificial intelligence, as President Xi Jinping held talks with President Vladimir Putin in Beijing.
The Russian leader is in China to attend the Shanghai Cooperation Organization Summit and commemorations of the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
The leaders of China, Russia, and Mongolia had a three-way meeting where President Xi proposed deeper trust and cooperation.
In his separate talks with Mongolian president, Ufna Hurasukh, Xi Jinping called on both sides to take the building of a community with a shared future as the guiding principle.
President Xi also held talks with more world leaders ahead of the V-day events.
China's top political adviser has called the victory in the war of resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War a great achievement of all Chinese people, including compatriots from Hong Kong, Macau, Taiwan, and overseas.
Chairman Wang Huning of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference National Committee attended a symposium in Beijing.
He stressed the importance of promoting China's national spirit and the spirit of resistance and working together to advance Chinese modernization and realize national rejuvenation.
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu says Israel is entering the decisive stage of the war in Gaza.
He made the announcement as he was seeking to rally support among reservists and counter reports of low turnout for the latest call-up.
Netanyahu said the military campaign has advanced Israel toward a sweeping victory.
Israel has summoned about 40,000 reservists as part of its plan to capture Gaza City, the largest single call-up since the war began nearly two years ago.
But media reports said the turnout was lower than expected.
Over 350 reservists also announced in a letter that they will refuse to serve if ordered into Gaza, denouncing the government's decision to take over Gaza City as reckless and vowing not to take part.
Banned weather and infrastructure are hampering rescue efforts in western Sudan following a landslide.
At least 1,000 people are dead after being buried in a mountainous area hit by torrential rains.
A suicide car bomb has targeted the headquarters of Libya's 444th combat brigade in Bani Walid.
The brigade said in a statement that a suicide tanker detonated himself inside a car in front of the headquarters.
It said the situation is under control and that the headquarters continues to perform its duties.
And that's the news.
I'm Do Hongyu.
Thanks for watching.
I hope you enjoyed this video.
I'm going to be back in a few minutes.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye.