Now the news, I'm Tianyu.
China and the African Union have plashed to strengthen solidarity in building a more just global governance system and a peaceful world.
The commitment was made at a high-level seminar in Addis Ababa marking the 80th anniversary of the victory in the Chinese People's War of Resistance against Japanese aggression and the World Anti-Fascist War.
The head of the Chinese mission to the AU emphasized the need to remember history and enhance global cooperation to address security challenges.
Jiang Feng also called on the global south to jointly uphold multilateralism.
Iranian Foreign Minister Said Abbas Aranqi says Tehran and the International Atomic Energy Agency are very close to agreeing on a new framework for the resumption of bilateral cooperation.
He also noted that Iran will begin to talk with the United States when Washington is ready for negotiations based on common interests and mutual respect.
The two sides were scheduled to hold indirect nuclear negotiations on June 15 in Oman.
The talks were suspended after Israel and the U.S. launched air strikes on key Iranian sides.
As a response, the Iranian parliament overwhelmingly passed a law to suspend cooperation with the IAEA.
South Korean President Lee Jae-myun has ordered a full response after over 300 Korean workers were arrested in a U.S. immigration raid.
The operation took place at a Hyundai Motor Car Battery Plant in Georgia on Thursday.
More than 470 people were detained in the raid, the largest single-site enforcement action in U.S. Department of Homeland Security's history.
People activists estimate that 80% of the residents in Gaza City have chosen not to leave despite Israel's order to move south ahead of an offensive to capture Gaza's largest urban center.
Residents say the south is already overcrowded and they cannot afford transportation.
Israel has announced a humanitarian zone in Hong-Yunis that it says will ensure the continued delivery of food, tents, and medicine.
Palestinian sources said Israel has been targeting residential towers in Gaza City.
The military destroyed two high-rise towers, claiming Hamas used them to monitor Israeli troops.
An Ebola outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo has killed at least 15 people.
There are among the 28 people with symptoms since the DRC declared an outbreak on Thursday.
Chris Okamringa has more.
The first patient was a 34-year-old pregnant woman admitted to hospital last month with symptoms of fever and vomiting.
She later died along with 14 others, including four health workers.
Samples tested confirmed the Zaire strain of Ebola.
Scientists say the virus is often transmitted from infected animals such as fruit bats and spreads rapidly through direct contact with infected people.
The DRC Health Ministry is working with the World Health Organization and the Africa Center for Disease Control to trace contacts and provide treatment.
The World Health Organization has warned that infections could rise further.
Neighboring Uganda said it is on high alert and authorities will conduct a risk assessment.
U.S. President Donald Trump had said he will not attend the G20 summit in South Africa later this year.
However, Trump said he plans to send Vice President J.D. Vance in his place.
The U.S. President also said the country will host next year's G20 summit at his golf club near Miami.
Europe has launched a supercomputer claimed to be the world's fourth fastest.
German Chancellor Fritz Merz says the historic project has helped Europe catch up with the U.S. and China, both leading the AI race.
The Jupiter is the region's fastest supercomputer.
In tennis, Arena Sabalanka defeated local favorite Amanda Anisimova in straight sets to win the U.S. Open.
The Belarusian player took her Grand Slam tally to four after successfully defending her title at Flushing medals.
Yannick Sinner and Carlos Ocaras will play for the men's title.
Xin Julei has won the Best Actress Award at the Venus Film Festival for her role in The Sun Rises on Us All.
The Chinese actress encouraged all girls to chase their dreams in her acceptance speech.
The film portrays a tragic romance.
And that's the news.
I'm Tian Yu.